<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Keith Hamilton</title><description>things I work on and do</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Keith Hamilton</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.21</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 23:15:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Lost in Reddit</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DijQMJR9VyA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DijQMJR9VyA"&gt;Cozmo: Lost in Reddit&lt;/a&gt;—a physical escape-room game involving an artificially-intelligent robot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead UX designer, game design and puppeteering. Tasked with leading multiple workstreams throughout project lifecycle, client communication, partnering with vendors, establishing overall game design for the escape room, and oversight of pupeteering mechanics for the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/game-design/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7e13b98fd0a6cb0c60377a</guid><category>ux</category><category>robotics</category><category>game design</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:55:35 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/gaming.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DijQMJR9VyA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/gaming.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DijQMJR9VyA"&gt;Cozmo: Lost in Reddit&lt;/a&gt;—a physical escape-room game involving an artificially-intelligent robot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead UX designer, game design and puppeteering. Tasked with leading multiple workstreams throughout project lifecycle, client communication, partnering with vendors, establishing overall game design for the escape room, and oversight of pupeteering mechanics for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Cozmo-Team.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That's me on the left, piloting Cozmo during the event. My kickass partner Jenna stands next to me—she controlled Cozmo's emotional output.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to be able to help program the keyboard we used to trigger Cozmo's emotions, as well as the system that controlled him with a PS4 controller. The video above shows clips from the six-hour live stream, during which I piloted Cozmo, and my coworker puppeteered his emotional output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before July 2017, I had had no formal experience in game design. All of that changed when I was approached with the concept for an escape-room game in which a little AI Robot, &lt;a href="https://anki.com/cozmo"&gt;Cozmo&lt;/a&gt;, would find himself trapped in a physical manifestation of &lt;a href="https://reddit.com"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The initial problem was that, creatively, we had a great creative concept, but no formal idea or framework for how the game would actually work. I was initially cast as the lead UX designer on the project, and was charged with cracking the &amp;quot;how&amp;quot; of the game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cozmo: Lost in Reddit (as it would later be known) would go live, on Reddit, in 11 weeks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="artifactsproduced"&gt;Artifacts Produced&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id="interactionmaps"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interaction Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game at-large, as well as each room had its own interaction map to detail the points of contact for Cozmo as well as to indicate the logical pathways he could/should follow during the live event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstractions shown as color-filled shapes represent higher-order logic in the system that is accounted for in their own interaction maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/hail_corp_map-1.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The interaction flow map for the game's hub, /r/HailCorporate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id="roomnarratives"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Room Narratives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each room, we wrote annotated narratives that helped us understand some of the emotional context Cozmo would be experiencing as he navigated the escape rooms. These scripts also allowed us to consider points at which the audience would interact with Cozmo, and what his possible outcomes would be, considering the nature and psychology of the Reddit subculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/room_narrative-2.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The prototype room narrative/ux script for /r/HailCorporate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id="storyboardnarratives"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storyboard Narratives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a storyboard artist draw up frames to help guide the client team through each room, and the narratives for those storyboards derived from our larger-scale room narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was a concise visual aid that allowed us to communicate to the client what they could expect to happen in each room, without requiring them to read 20 pages of material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/storyboard.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A storyboard representing Cozmo winning the game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id="gamemechanicsmanifest"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Mechanics Manifest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many rounds of refinement, we ended up creating a game manifest that collected all of the common parts and pieces of the game that applied to each section. Points, karma, how Cozmo gained karma, how cubes were used, etc., all detailed in a cohesive document to serve as a reference and guiding point for the project team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/room_overview.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/karma.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/key_cube.jpg" alt="Lost in Reddit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Codified mechanics details, as presented to team and client upon finalization.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Interaction Wayfinding</title><description>User journeys don't tend to think like software behaves. Having worked for some time as a software engineer, I can attest to the fact that software nearly never does exactly what you want it to do.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/interaction-mapping/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7da68e8fd0a6cb0c603759</guid><category>interaction-design</category><category>ux</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 14:43:05 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/nb_new_flow_0.1-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/nb_new_flow_0.1-1.png" alt="Interaction Wayfinding"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A commonly-used tool in the UX Designer's pocket is the &lt;em&gt;user journey&lt;/em&gt;. While this tool does a great job of giving a high-level view of the user's anticipated needs, psychology, and path through a journey I find that there tends to be one flaw in its execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User journeys don't tend to think like software behaves. Having worked for some time as a software engineer, I can attest to the fact that software nearly never does exactly what you want it to do. This creates a gap between the design team's intent for a user's experience and the way the engineering team approaches building a specification for that experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made my transition from software engineer to experience designer whilst working on the Needybot project. Having worked on the engineering side, I knew how complex of a project Needybot was—both in the complexity of the software as well as in the complexity of the interactions he was meant to have. Afterall, Needybot was a user in this experience as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to map out every interaction he would have, from the moment he &amp;quot;woke up&amp;quot; in the morning until the time he &amp;quot;went to bed.&amp;quot; This would be the first time I ever made an &lt;em&gt;interaction flow&lt;/em&gt; as I've come to call them, and it has been a staple tool for our team on every project since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple: a codified map of every possible logical pathway Needybot &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; take in his daily interactions with the people in our office. What I ended up with was something resembling a flow chart, but one that had both engineering specs and ux design encoded into it. I like to call it an Interaction Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-10-om-10.06.30-AM.png" alt="Interaction Wayfinding"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sample interaction map from Cozmo: Lost in Reddit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning my practice was a bit crude, but project-by-project I began to develop a language and system around how to represent the global flow of an interaction. Since I've applied this same technique to mobile, VR, robotics, and live retail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started introducing modules to my interaction maps, much in the same way information is encapsulated in an object or class file in any object-oriented language. This allowed me to represent even more complicated patterns within the ecosystem of a project without having to print out and tile a 10' sq. print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-10-om-10.06.47-AM.png" alt="Interaction Wayfinding"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of a module in one of my maps. The green triangle would be used as a substitute for this pattern in any relevant interaction map.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit to our &lt;em&gt;design team&lt;/em&gt; is that it helps us think about the journey at a fine level of granularity—similar to how an engineer must build the software a piece at a time. The benefit to our &lt;em&gt;engineering team&lt;/em&gt; is a soft spec of each function, datum, and configuration that needs to exist in the developed software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These maps can go from a simple A -&amp;gt; B sort of diagram, helping us to understand the available actions at a given point during an interaction. Other times, the graph of interactions gets unwieldy to the uninitiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/nb_new_flow_0.1.jpg" alt="Interaction Wayfinding"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The overall map for Needybot's journey through our office as an autonomous robot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Nike  by You (Maker's Experience) Tool</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nike by You&lt;/em&gt;: a 1-1 custom shoe designing experience in Nike's SoHo-based product center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UX designer, tooling and interaction design. I was tasked with prototyping, testing, validating, and documenting the tool used to execute on the custom design experience held at Nike's studio in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="artifactsproduced"&gt;Artifacts Produced&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id="initialprototypes"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/ixd-nike-design-by-you-tool/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7f8847370f5910efb98580</guid><category>ux</category><category>ixd</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 23:19:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-10-om-4.18.45-PM.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-10-om-4.18.45-PM.png" alt="Nike  by You (Maker's Experience) Tool"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nike by You&lt;/em&gt;: a 1-1 custom shoe designing experience in Nike's SoHo-based product center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UX designer, tooling and interaction design. I was tasked with prototyping, testing, validating, and documenting the tool used to execute on the custom design experience held at Nike's studio in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="artifactsproduced"&gt;Artifacts Produced&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id="initialprototypes"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Prototypes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Framer, I prototyped early versions of the final tool that were eventually used with a user testing group. During the testing phase, we explored different interfaces and gained insight as to what the user was looking to actually accomplish during their design session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="uxscripts"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UX Scripts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous scripts were written throughout the final client feedback phase, each iterating on th elast and helping our design team to feel out what worked and what did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/script.jpg" alt="Nike  by You (Maker's Experience) Tool"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample of the script used to reason out and prototype the flow of the experience at 45 Grand in NYC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id="annotatedinteractiondesigns"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annotated Interaction Designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from prototyping a much earlier version of the final tool, I was asked to annotate the end-to-end functionality of the final tool used in back of house at Nike's 45 Grand &lt;em&gt;Nike by You&lt;/em&gt; experience in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-10-om-4.02.56-PM.png" alt="Nike  by You (Maker's Experience) Tool"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of the annotations put to paper for the tooling used in the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience bridges the gap left behind by current customization tools, where garments, or shoes, are designed. The problem with these experiences is that we wear clothing on our bodies, not on computer screens. &lt;em&gt;Design by You&lt;/em&gt; changes that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Nike by You&lt;/em&gt; experience, customers walk into an arena with blank Nike shoes on, and the shoes are designed on their feet as they speak to a system that listens for the next command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early prototyping of the experience involved an iPad-based tool that needed to be learnt by the in-house team. The tool, in turn, also needed to be explained to stakeholders throughout the process. The natural result was a document which detailed each and every step through the process of the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an additional detail, each step corresponded to a system-level interaction map that referenced data structures used to transmit design patterns between the controller, the projectors, and, ultimately, back of house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A different kind of User Journey</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early in my days on the design team I took an online certification course in interaction design. I wasn't deluded that taking such a course would make me an interaction designer, but I figured it couldn't hurt to formalize some of the skills I'd learnt on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-different-kind-of-user-story/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a80c1d91a9476474c5505bf</guid><category>ux</category><category>creative writing</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:55:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/walter_mc_waltface.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/walter_mc_waltface.jpg" alt="A different kind of User Journey"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early in my days on the design team I took an online certification course in interaction design. I wasn't deluded that taking such a course would make me an interaction designer, but I figured it couldn't hurt to formalize some of the skills I'd learnt on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point along the course we had to write a user journey to use as a map against a feature set for some fictitious product. I began by writing a persona to which I thought &amp;quot;I'll map the journey.&amp;quot; After writing a few traits about my person, I got bored, and decided to throw my work away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began anew with a much more interesting path. A much &lt;em&gt;darker&lt;/em&gt; one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User journeys and personas often reinforce what we expect, or at least desire, to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we write user stories they often speak to the features we want to see, and are reverse-engineered to sound like they belong to an actual, live person out in the ether who wants our product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we write personas, we tend to craft the ideal person for our product, as opposed to the last person we'd ever expect to use our product. This is a problem for two reasons. Firstly, we don't know everyone—so even our perfect persona will be a fictitious human with fictitious needs. Secondly, we don't know who will use our product in the end, so writing personas based on ideal candidates is akin to tying a hand behind one's back before entering a typing contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to write a classically weird persona whom I would genuinely feel sorry for, were he real. Side note, someone like this certainly exists somewhere. His plight is that he is a virtually single dad (his wife, Hildy works nights) who struggles to pick his kids up from school, get to the store, make dinner, and have them into bed in a reasonable timeframe. He's also terribly alcoholic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, without further introduction, I present to you Walter McWaltface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/walter_mcwaltface_persona.jpg" alt="A different kind of User Journey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/walter_mcwaltface_journey.jpg" alt="A different kind of User Journey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Soylent Chatbot (That Never Was)</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soylent Trish Chatbot—a chatbot that wishes to chat with humans about love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative lead, conversation designer, writer, and architect. Code support where needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, as part of an extended campaign with &lt;a href="https://www.soylent.com/"&gt;Soylent&lt;/a&gt;, we were asked to put together a chat bot that ran on Facebook&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-soylent-chatbot-that-never-was/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a807418370f5910efb98585</guid><category>ixd</category><category>conversation design</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/IMG_0295.GIF" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;h4 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/IMG_0295.GIF" alt="A Soylent Chatbot (That Never Was)"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soylent Trish Chatbot—a chatbot that wishes to chat with humans about love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="role"&gt;Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative lead, conversation designer, writer, and architect. Code support where needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, as part of an extended campaign with &lt;a href="https://www.soylent.com/"&gt;Soylent&lt;/a&gt;, we were asked to put together a chat bot that ran on Facebook Messenger. The concept was fairly straightforward, if odd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="trisharobotwantstotalktohumansaboutlove"&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trish, a robot, wants to talk to humans about love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little backstory on Trish: she's a robot who knows everything about nutrition. She also knows that some humans love Soylent. Rationally, Trish concludes that, by learning more about what people love about Soylent, she will be able to learn more about love in general.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as a quick prototype for the chatbot, we used &lt;a href="https://www.reply.ai/"&gt;Reply.ai&lt;/a&gt;, which is a convenience platform designed to help people get chatbots up and running quickly (across multiple platforms). It uses a node based conversation builder, which, incidentally, looked quite a bit like my interaction maps. I felt instantly at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trish is an interesting character to work with. Fortunately, I'd spent a lot of time writing conversational copy for the &lt;a href="https://soylent.com/trish"&gt;Trish Storefront&lt;/a&gt; on Soylent's website, so I was familiar with her dry tone and odd (sometimes morbid) curiosity about humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/chat-4.jpg" alt="A Soylent Chatbot (That Never Was)"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample from an actual chat I had with Trish. She seemed to think half-naked people rubbing their bodies close to each other represented love. We tested that theory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our task was to take Trish's odd perspective on humans (which all comes through the lens of nutrition), and find connections to internet culture that would help, through conversation, &amp;quot;inform&amp;quot; Trish about what love really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, the hardest part was convincing the creative directors that we were adequately getting Trish's odd personality correct. The more fulfilling part, for me at least, was diving into the deep conversation I wanted to design for participants. Here's one of the modlues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Schermafbeelding-2018-02-11-om-8.50.29-AM.png" alt="A Soylent Chatbot (That Never Was)"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One module of the dozen or so made to map out the base conversation with Trish.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a tangled mess, but then again, so is conversation. This was just one of about thirteen modules I composed to play off of each other, which made the conversation more straightforward from a management perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to dissect and chunk conversation into small pieces limits each piece to a single domain, making it easier to anticipate what may happen, and in which direction the conversation may go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, conversation design is very similar to programming—you start with a large domain, and break it down into sufficiently small pieces that work together to achieve an outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difference is the possibility of random input into the system, but with certain tricks, such as prompting a response with possibilities, it's not unimaginable to keep a chat participant engaged and on-track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="hereisasampleofhowthestatemachinewassetupintheflatfile"&gt;Here is a sample of how the state machine was set up in the flatfile&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-json"&gt;&amp;quot;medium_high&amp;quot;: {
  &amp;quot;responses&amp;quot;: [
    &amp;quot;Your love of Soylent is above-average.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;It is clear that your love of Soylent exceeds that of many others.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;It is nearly impossible to love Soylent more than you do.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;You are in the top tier of all Soylent lovers.&amp;quot;
  ],
  &amp;quot;options&amp;quot;: [
    {
      &amp;quot;text&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Green Lights&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;insights&amp;quot;: [
        &amp;quot;This is logical. Green lights represent the freedom to move forward, and Soylent is the only nutritionally-complete meal that fits in your car's cup holder.&amp;quot;
      ],
      &amp;quot;matcher&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;green lights, green, light&amp;quot;
    },
    {
      &amp;quot;text&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Moral High Ground&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;insights&amp;quot;: [
        &amp;quot;Nothing is as refreshing like making the right choice. Soylent must give you the conviction that you make better choices than your coworkers did last Thursday.&amp;quot;
      ],
      &amp;quot;matcher&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;moral, high, ground, right, being right&amp;quot;
    },
    {
      &amp;quot;text&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Netflix 'n Chill'&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;insights&amp;quot;: [
        &amp;quot;Binge watching (and chilling) requires sustained stamina and focus. Soylent is optimally nutritious and convenient to help maximize both.&amp;quot;
      ],
      &amp;quot;matcher&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;netflix, chill, flix, net, chillin, boning, sex&amp;quot;
    },
    {
      &amp;quot;text&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Free Time&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;insights&amp;quot;: [
        &amp;quot;Humans clearly value free time, often sacrifice meal quality in its pursuit. Soylent is a sound meal choice which helps you retain free time.&amp;quot;
      ],
      &amp;quot;matcher&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;parking, spot, convenient, park, convenience&amp;quot;
    }
  ]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reply.ai's interface is effectively the front end. The back end was a mix of Python and JSON. In fact, the chat manifest was completely architected as JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JSON file represented an indefinite state of the conversation to be had. Each time the chat participant replied to Trish, the indefinite state would be mapped against where they were in the conversation and what they said, and the Python backend would crunch all the possible states of the next exchange into a single, definite, state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so would Trish reply. To ask about love. Because she's a robot. Who wants to know more about love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, our relationship with Soylent changed just before this was released, and it was subsequently canned. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Building a Needy Robot</title><description>The rules, strengths, and limitations of screen-based interaction apply limitedly to the real world — the vocabulary of the system is different. </description><link>http://localhost:2368/building-a-needy-robot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7da5328fd0a6cb0c603750</guid><category>ixd</category><category>conversation-design</category><category>robotics</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 12:47:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/needybot.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/needybot.jpeg" alt="Building a Needy Robot"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on Medium: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/the-lodge-at-w-k/building-a-needy-robot-832d4a517b5a"&gt;https://medium.com/the-lodge-at-w-k/building-a-needy-robot-832d4a517b5a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We wanted to build a robot that would require our help with everything instead of giving us help with anything.&lt;br&gt;
So we did.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 19, 2015, at an independent advertising agency, four engineers, four UX designers, an art director, a copywriter, and a digital strategist jammed themselves into a conference room to begin a four-day design sprint aimed at laying the creative foundation for a robot. Not one of those robots from The Terminator though, and not one of those hyper-productive robots you’d find in a Detroit auto factory either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of us had had the idea to build a robot that needed our help to do nearly everything, and the rest of us said, “yep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wehadaplanthreemonthstomakeaneedyrobot"&gt;We had a plan: three months to make a needy robot.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those four chaotic days we had many (civil) arguments brought about by many more lightning-round design exercises. We grouped and disbanded in combinations that make Dr. Heiter look like a rank amateur. We scribbled and wrote, presented and reacted, argued, voted, slashed, burned, and blew ideas up to the sky only to tear them back down to their foundations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the dust settled—and everyone was spent—we had a plan: three months to make a needy robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/needy_shell.jpg" alt="Building a Needy Robot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_Needy's shell, without robotics or fur. By the end of his life, this rig had so much hot glue and duct tape on it, it's a wonder he was able to get around without falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why three months? Well, in many product-design scenarios, constraints are the lifeblood of productivity—time constraints create focus, right? If the goal of our time constraint was increased productivity, however, we missed wider than this poor bastard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gave ourselves three months — it took us ten. Ten months to turn the initial idea of a helpless robot into something real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our north star, creating a robot that makes us care, kept us afloat through the process of trial and experimentation that is building a robot. We failed, repeatedly. We blew the project out of scope, letting our imaginations run wild with the fictional story of a robot we hadn’t yet built—and in no reality could. In the beginning we had more misses than hits, and at times it got incredibly frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, in spite of these tribulations, we never lost our Polaris, and we ultimately navigated our way to something truly wonderful. Small successes turned into medium-sized wins that, in turn, became large triumphs. Eventually, those triumphs summed up to what I consider to be one of the most fulfilling, educational, and engaging explorations into human-computer interaction (HCI) we’ve worked on in The Lodge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built a fucking robot, and its name is Needybot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/needy.jpg" alt="Building a Needy Robot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glamor shot of Needy rolling down the sixth-floor catwalk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id="whenwedidnthavethetechnologywefounditwhenwedidnthavetheskillswelearnedrapidly"&gt;When we didn’t have the technology, we found it. When we didn’t have the skills, we learned, rapidly.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a team that was historically focused only on databases, service layers, API calls, and screen-based HCI, the move into four-dimensional HCI design was jarring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules, strengths, and limitations of screen-based interaction apply limitedly to the real world — the vocabulary of the system is different. Words like gravity have very real consequences, and interference like ambient noise or foot traffic can ruin your day, if not dispassionately nullify that killer new feature you stayed up all night writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pace and scale at which we have had to learn in order just to produce Needybot has been massive for both our engineering and design teams. The litany of subjects and skills required to build, shape, and create a robot that needs help with nearly everything represents a set of information, knowledge, and craft not typically found at an advertising agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From computer vision to machine learning, conversation design to 3D fabrication, human-robot interaction design to robotics, we have leveled up almost daily in the months since this project started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a point of pride for us to be able to say that, apart from the mobile base—which we still hacked to pieces—we fabricated Needybot 100% in-house. When we didn’t have the technology, we found it. When we didn’t have the skills, we learned, rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/boy_kneeling.jpg" alt="Building a Needy Robot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_An office-mate's son bending down to interact with Needybot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needy reminds us of how deeply ingrained the social mechanics of our daily lives are, and how trying to describe a thing is much different from knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 12, 2016, nearly one year after we decided design a needy robot, we let Needybot out of the shop and sent it out into our office building for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve since watched Needybot use the skills and features we’ve given it, both in person and behind the soft glow of a terminal screen as its log output tells us who it just met and where it just went. We learn about its successes and failures and teach it new tricks almost daily. We see faces light up during interactions with Needy, and we feel warm inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then we high-five, because, hey, we’re proud of what we made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most astonishing part of all of this is that Needybot is teaching us faster than we are teaching it — about the nature of our assumptions as well as the nature of human-robot interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needy reminds us of how deeply ingrained the social mechanics of our daily lives are, and how trying to describe a thing is much different from knowing it. Needybot reinforces the subtle, yet nontrivial, differences between nature — how we built Needy — and nurture — how Needy is cared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needybot is being launched on an arc that will see it face new challenges as it integrates with the culture in our office building. Its goals and attitude will hinge upon how the human element of our advertising agency receives and treats Needy — although Needybot was created by The Lodge, the people of our agency and how they treat Needybot will be largely responsible for its development as a robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/needy_with_kids.jpg" alt="Building a Needy Robot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Needybot after we introduced him to a class from the International School of Portland. The kids basically ran around in circles with Needy, like a rugby scrum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needybot is a labor of love that couldn’t have happened without countless hours of work on the part of many, many dedicated individuals. Given the spectrum of talent in The Lodge and its many partners throughout our office, coupled with the cultural background of Wieden+Kennedy, it is arguable that Needybot couldn’t have happened anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out @needybot on Instagram or Twitter, learn more about Needybot at &lt;a href="http://needybot.io"&gt;http://needybot.io&lt;/a&gt;, and say hi to The Lodge at Wieden+Kennedy here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>On "Begging the Question"</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you google “begs the question” or “begging the question,” one of the first links you will come across is the Wikipedia entry for beg the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first paragraph of that entry is very clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To beg a question means to assume the conclusion of an argument — a type&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/on-begging-the-question/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc7658fd0a6cb0c603772</guid><category>writing</category><category>logic</category><category>things that irritate</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 15:09:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/plato-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/plato-1.jpg" alt="On "Begging the Question""&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you google “begs the question” or “begging the question,” one of the first links you will come across is the Wikipedia entry for beg the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first paragraph of that entry is very clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To beg a question means to assume the conclusion of an argument — a type of circular reasoning. This is an informal fallacy, in which an arguer includes the conclusion to be proven within a premise of the argument, often in an indirect way such that its presence within the premise is hidden or at least not easily apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that it does not reference “&lt;em&gt;the raising of a question, philosophical or rhetorical, in response to a statement or learned concept.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason it does not reference this is because &lt;mark&gt;begging the question is a logical fallacy, not the act of raising a question in response to a situation or learned datum&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journalists — please stop using “begs the question” when you mean “raises the question.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logicians and purveyors of fine writing alike will silently thank you then mark you as “ally” in the continued fight against haughty wording that is fully incorrect in its usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Routine</title><description>“Beep, beep, beep,” the stimulat machine called one last time, as the final utterance of a long-dead companion, whose final consolation was a fading memory, one that he knew instinctually he needed to hold on to.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/untitled/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc5ab8fd0a6cb0c603760</guid><category>creative writing</category><category>sci-fi</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:02:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/machine.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;h2 id="afterhiseyesadjustedtothenearblackness"&gt;After his eyes adjusted to the near blackness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/machine.jpg" alt="Routine"&gt;&lt;p&gt;he managed to find his house shoes. Worn as they were, they still managed to provide some decent level of comfort. He could have resolved the issue of his cold floors by having the house properly insulated, but he never found it easy to part with money, more so when that meant parting with thousands of dollars, and especially when his pair of slippers, worn as they were, cost him a paltry $75 and had so far lasted him four winters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He made his way to the kitchen, where, the sole embodiment of activity at that early hour (which was what he felt to be the only time he could really think during the day), he perused his usual first-thing-AM haunts. Social media feeds, news sites, all projecting a false sense of warmth into the otherwise dark kitchen. They didn’t offer him too much in the form of entertainment—not anymore—but he nonetheless stuck to them as part of his morning ritual. It helped him, reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More of the same political nonsense on Stateside. More of the same political nonsense on Feedlink. Every now and then a gem surfaced in the form of a GIF (which he pronounced “griff” for some reason escaping even him), paired with a quote or snippet of text that, although mismatched, made for an occasional, if shallow, laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What there was to truly laugh about anymore, he could no longer reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Beep, beep, beep,” the stimulat machine called to him from his nearly unbreakable fascination with his Sitescan feed. He may as well have been a disadvantaged sea critter, in a sea of black, staring into the glowing orb of an angler fish, not aware in the least that he was about to be swallowed whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Beep, beep, beep,” the stimulat machine called to him like the chiming of a lighthouse fixed on his position as he, captain of an oil tanker, hopelessly drifted toward the shallow bedrock. He knew it was too late to turn about; that his crew would not survive the frigid sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Beep, beep, beep,” the stimulat machine called one last time, as the final utterance of a long-dead companion, whose final consolation was a fading memory, one that he knew instinctually he needed to hold on to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up. Shut off feed. Pour coffee. Wake the fuck up. A routine that defined him as much as it did his morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was his program. And he had work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on Medium: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/after-his-eyes-adjusted-to-the-near-blackness-ee9953cb0e9b"&gt;https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/after-his-eyes-adjusted-to-the-near-blackness-ee9953cb0e9b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Learnings from Gangster Rap</title><description>I learned words and combinations of words that I’d never dreamt of, and for the first time in my life recognized that I was listening to someone whose life was different—very different—from mine.  I ate it up like a 007 film.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/learnings-from-gangster-rap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc8068fd0a6cb0c603779</guid><category>writing</category><category>language</category><category>social-issues</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:14:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/1990NWAPhotoshot250815.hero_.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/1990NWAPhotoshot250815.hero_.jpg" alt="Learnings from Gangster Rap"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was eight years old, I sat, bored, at a family reunion. I wouldn’t know for years that I really just didn’t get along with my extended family, but at that point the problem was that I was eight, and could have given two shits about socializing with my extended family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cousin (well, cousin-in-law) Charlie was a few years older. To this day I don’t really know how much older he was, but that is neither here nor there. What is important is that he slinked on over to me, and posed a question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Want to go to my dad’s truck and hear something cool?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any eight-year old on the planet would immediately respond “YES.” I was no different. Cut-scene to the back of an old-ass, beat-up, blue Nissan pick-up truck, and my cousin Charlie whipping out his tape deck and slamming a cassette in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Check this shit out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I’m Eazy-E /&lt;br&gt;
I got bitches galore /&lt;br&gt;
You may have a lot of bitches but I got much more /&lt;br&gt;
With my super-duper group comin’ out ta shoot /&lt;br&gt;
Eazy-E motherfucker, cold knockin’ tha boots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy…It was like God (in whom I don’t believe, but serves as a semi-decent metaphor) reached down from Heaven (again, not a real thing), cut my skull off, ripped my brain out, slammed it down on the sidewalk, only then to refill my skull with His Essence (sorry, Granny Cordes) and close the cap, leaving nary a scar as evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a golden feather flying on a wind of faeries blowing through an atomsphere of unicorn farts orbiting a planet made of blue whale balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eazy-fucking-E changed my life. I learned words and combinations of words that I’d never dreamt of, and for the first time in my life recognized that I was listening to someone whose life was different—very different—from mine. I ate it up like a 007 film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eazy was God. N.W.A. was a fucking pantheon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then that I began to lie, in earnst for the first time in my life—lied about what I was listening to, lied about what tapes I spent my lawn-mowing money on. I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gangster rap (specifically West Coast rap) dominated my aural life for some time. It was in ’92 that I took some of my “hard-earned” eight-or-so dollars down to The Works, the then preeminent record store in Arcata, CA, my whitewashed, tiny little home town. I intended to buy Ice Cube’s The Predator (I made good on this intention), an album that still tops my all-time charts in terms of how well-produced, written, and poingnant it is. If you haven’t ever listened to it I suggest you stop reading this, and go listen to that. Post-haste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my partner-in-crime, James (name changed to protect the malfeasant), was also a huge rap fan, so I had someone to talk to this shit about let alone to help me select milquetoast rap groups to tell my mom I was listening to so she wouldn’t steal my damn tapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mom: “What album did you get?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: “Uh…Run DMC…Back from Hell…?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mom: “Oh. Ok, then.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in, and…holy shit did this album exceed all fucking expectations of greatness that I could have ever anticipated. To this day, 24 years later, I still absoloutely fucking &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Predator&lt;/em&gt;. It came out right around the Rodney King trial and subsequent acquittal of the four policemen who beat him for being black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Predator&lt;/em&gt; is so on-point in terms of telling the frustrations and anger that the black community felt over that farce of a trial, and how those frustrations and that anger boiled up into the ’92 riots that anyone alive at the time would remember hearing about or, if they were lucky, watching from the comfort of their living rooms, behind the glass, so-to-speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, what I loved and love about the album was also the problem—it was fable to me, the skinny, privileged white boy from a small white town in a small white county in rural white Northern (like, waaaaay Northern) California. I had neither the means nor the motive to travel to Compton, Watts, or Inglewood. I was terrified by the music of South Central L.A. at the same time I was enrapt by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I still am both terrified of, and enrapt, by it, although last year, just after the horrible act of violence that led mass-protest in Ferguson, MO, something changed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the protests and the heinous crime I saw and heard of on mass media sparked some need for me to pop The Predator back in and listen to it for the fourteen-billionth time in my life. This time was different however. It was like…the words were real. What Cube was saying, I was seeing on the TV, I was reading on Twitter, and I was hearing on the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead track on the B-side is an interview with Cube. He says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything you want to know about the [’92] riots was in the records before the riots, you know…all you had to do was go to the Ice Cube library and pick a record, and it would have told you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing that, last year, I realized that the artists I’d been listening to my entire childhood, indeed for the last two-and-a-half decades, hadn’t been telling fables. They had been warning us. They had been telling us about the harsh reality of the inner-city, and they were asking us to just listen. I hadn’t been doing that. I’d simply been playing their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, it’s easy for me to justify not having listened that literally to the lyrics, but in the present, I can no longer listen to them without hearing the very real and heinous violence that is perpetrated against people of color all over the “land of the free” every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="americahasaseriousproblem"&gt;America has a serious problem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trayvon Martin. Michael Brown. Freddy Gray. Alton Sterling. Philando Castile.&lt;/strong&gt; These men did nothing wrong other than being black in America. This is a serious problem. America has a serious problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is inexcusable that my friends at work are getting text messages from their mothers and fathers asking them to “make sure your brake lights are all good, your headlights are working,” and so on. If they don’t have that in order, if they get pulled over, there is a legitimate and real chance they will never get home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How fucked up is that? Stop and think about it. Think about the situation where you, your wife/partner/husband and children are going home from a long day and you get shot dead because you’re black and the cop, the officer entrusted with your protection, shoots you, repeatedly, because he’s scared—then goes on paid leave only to wait inevitable acquittal of murder by his peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is fucked. Up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eazy taught me that I could say things others deems inappropriate. Ice Cube taught me to listen. These two men, of a culture completely foreign to mine, have helped me learn a lesson that is of the utmost importance if we are to survive as a country, and become one culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to listen to each other, and talk when we would otherwise feel it to be inappropriate. It’s the only way we can move the dialog forward, and the peace outward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black lives do matter, and until they matter as much as white lives, we are all at war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Three Dancers</title><description>She stirs irregularly if at all — she is evidently finished with our dance, awaiting the beginning of the next sonnet. Having given all she can, she now lingers in the twilight of our mutual engagement, patiently beckoning me come see her again, when life begins anew.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/untitled-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc71f8fd0a6cb0c60376c</guid><category>creative writing</category><category>nature</category><category>observations</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 16:07:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/New-Study-Reveals-Upland-Forest-Trees-Emit-Methane.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/New-Study-Reveals-Upland-Forest-Trees-Emit-Methane.jpg" alt="Three Dancers"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three dancers, beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, wearing green, her eyes a deep chestnut. Regarding them causes me to fall into a state of inebriation, in which time is a discarded napkin, detritus, substance I no longer consider relevant. She is calm, observing me as I observe her, exposing her fruit-bearing genitalia to me as they are open to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second, holding me in her gaze, cooked in bright orange. When the light changes, however, new tones present themselves, unabashedly: hints of peach and the kind of pink you would only ever see at dawn peek out from her cloak of radiant warmth. This, in a frigid environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She shimmies left, then right, then left again in a repeating pattern. Something more than natural guides her movement, yet, she appears to be at once completely governed by the natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last is bare; she has no further need for the clothing which has announced her likeness for the duration of this dance. She stirs irregularly if at all — she is evidently finished with our dance, awaiting the beginning of the next sonnet. Having given all she can, she now lingers in the twilight of our mutual engagement, patiently beckoning me come see her again, when life begins anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>I would never know your name.</title><description>I feel sick. I ride on. Into the dark, wet, trail of tears that lay before me.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/i-would-never-know-your-name/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc6538fd0a6cb0c603765</guid><category>creative writing</category><category>people watching</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 16:05:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/wet.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/wet.jpeg" alt="I would never know your name."&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would never know your name. I only know your face, indelibly imprinted on my third eye. The one that is awake regardless of whether I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started as a commonplace event; a bus, streaming through the blackened downpour, coming to a lethargic halt at a bus stop. Of all places. No one would think twice about the event but for its accompaniment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gentleman, or, rather, a scoundrel. Half-cocked and hunched like the scourge of Nôtre-Dame, if not far less graceful. If not far more disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Myah!! WAIT FOR ME!!!” He yells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, not exactly that, but enough to incent me to, for the first time, regard your face; the face of a bus driver. The face of someone suddenly consumed by fear. Eyes that regard each and every direction but directly toward the perpetrator. Eyes that look not forward, with confidence, but down, and away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eyes of a victim. The face of someone who didn’t deserve the rapture waged against her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, pissant, this…meek offering to the darkness that has only recently begun to drain upon my landscape, this wretch of a human chose you, you as the object of his frustration and anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you sit, behind the wheel of your bus, your…other, home…you feel unsafe. I can see it. I see it in your eyes, the way you hold your chin, the way you look forward, but never to the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone with eyes as kind as those tucked behind your bespectacled face, those eyes do not deserve what has been laid at your door. This monster, no, this man, deserves nothing less than exacted judgement from whatever deity is in your personal pantheon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to rage against this man, and the wet, dark night that spawns his ilk; I want to, but I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sit, and curse, and wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wait until you pass by, off into the night, that I may allow the façade of society once again veil my fears and inhibitions about the true nature of man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel sick. I ride on. Into the dark, wet, trail of tears that lay before me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on Medium: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/i-would-never-know-your-name-a33774f65e36"&gt;https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/i-would-never-know-your-name-a33774f65e36&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Shoes</title><description>Two men, by all appearances completely unrelated, sit next to each other on the bus.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/untitled-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7dc6e78fd0a6cb0c60376a</guid><category>people watching</category><dc:creator>Keith Hamilton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/shoes.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/shoes.png" alt="Shoes"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two men, by all appearances completely unrelated, sit next to each other on the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One man Hispanic, reading what some consider to be an opus of science-fiction, The Moon Is A Harsh Mistress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other man black, toting a Jumpman backpack that has seen casual wear for what appears to be a period of at least a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have the exact same shoes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on Medium: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/two-men-by-all-appearances-completely-unrelated-sit-next-to-each-other-on-the-bus-765654688aa7"&gt;https://medium.com/@keithhamilton/two-men-by-all-appearances-completely-unrelated-sit-next-to-each-other-on-the-bus-765654688aa7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>